A Finding Aid to the Tomás Ybarra-Frausto Research Material on Chicano Art, 1965-2004, in the Archives of American Art AAA.ybartoma
Archives of American Art
- Subject Files, 1965-1997; Series 1
  - Rodríguez, Jesús, 1972, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    (letter to Rodríguez from Joseph L. McCarthy, Dean, Graduate School Office, University of Washington, 04/17/1972, cc: TYF; letter to TYF from Rodríguez, 03/10/1977)
  - Rodríguez Guerra, José Luis, 1989, 2004; (exhibition announcements; invitations) (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - Rodríguez, Isis, 2002 (Box 24, Folder 32)
    (essay by Rodríguez)
  - Rodríguez, Laura, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 33)
    (photocopy of letter to "Whom it May Concern" from TYF, 09/12/1988, in support of a film being made by Rodríguez)
  - Rodríguez, Patricia (see also: Alters - Arte Chicano; Chicano Studies), 1981-1992 (Box 24, Folder 34)
    (resume; clippings; exhibition announcements; handwritten and typescript drafts of essay on Rodríguez by TYF; TYF's notes on Rodríguez; catalogs; resume; clippings; letter to TYF from Rodríguez, 06/07/1983; exhibition poster with note to TYF from Rodríguez on the back, circa 01/1982)
  - Rodríguez, Pedro (Peter) A. (see also: Mesa-Bains, Amalia), 1975-1992, undated (Box 24, Folder 35)
    (exhibition announcements; Christmas card to TYF and Dudley from Rodríguez, 12/1991; drawing by Rodríguez; clippings; letter to TYF from Rodríguez, 11/29/1992; b/w photograph of Rodríguez; catalogs; note to TYF from Rodríguez, undated; photocopy of galley proof for Who's Who in American Art; letter to TYF from Rodríguez, 10/24/1983; resume; postcard to TYF from Rodríguez, 02/02/1989)
  - Romano, Octavio Ignacio, 1960-1968, undated (Box 24, Folder 36)
    (clippings; typescripts of essays; reprint of essay; "Chicano crossword")
  - Romero, Alejandro (see also: Galería sin Fronteras; Mexican Fine Arts Center Museum), 1986-1991, undated (Box 24, Folder 37)
    (exhibition announcements; artist biography; catalog; "Chicano Art Exhibition Panel Member's List" including TYF's name)
  - Romero Cash, Marie, 2003; (exhibition announcement) (Box 24, Folder 38)
  - Romero, Ann, 1983; (clipping) (Box 24, Folder 39)
  - Romero, Frank (see also: Los Four; Luján, Gilbert Sanchez; Garza, Carmen Lomas; Martínéz, César; Vargas, Kathy; OV 32), 1984, 1993; (clippings; oversize exhibition poster; exhibition anouncement) (Box 24, Folder 40)
  - Rosado, Angel Suarez (see: Suarez, Angel) (Box 24)
  - Royal Chicano Air Force (RCAF) (Box 24)
    - General, 1976-1998, undated; (3 folders; see also: Centro de Artistas Chicanos; Goldman, Shifra; La Raza Bookstore; Montoya, José; Murals; Box 30) (Box 24, Folder 41-43)
      (TYF's notes on RCAF; clippings; photographs of works of art; flyers; Neighborhood Art Programs National Organizing Committee (NAPNOC) case study of the Centro de Artistas Chicanos; La Raza Bookstore publication catalog; exhibition announcements; Centro de Artistas Chicanos history; essay by Sam Rios, Dept. of Anthropology, California State University; photocopy of photograph of the RCAF group; letter to TYF from Sam Rios, 09/1981; oversized clippings from 1975 Calandario Chicano; letter to TYF from Mary Malit, Museum Secretary Crocker Art Museum, 04/29/1985, re. catalog/brochure on the 1983 Centro de Artistas Chicanos exhibition; typescript of essay by Shifra Goldman, "Chicano Art Looking Backward"; theater performance poster; letter to TYF from [?] Romo, 01/20/1978, re. TYF's participation in a poetry reading; booklet with short writings by Ricardo Favel, José Montoya, Luis Valdez; photocopy of poem by José Montoya; part of Ricardo Favela's Masters Thesis on the RCAF Retrospective Poster Art Exhibition)
    - Murals/SACTO, Notes, 1973, undated (Box 24, Folder 44)
      (book of Chicano poetry and art: Poemasomenos De Sacra, La Raza Bookstore, Sacramento, California, 1973; TYF's notes: list of sources, handwritten introduction for "The Chicano Mural Movement"; Centro de Artistas Chicanos illustration, "Chicano Brain Cell En El Mar"; extract from an essay, "El Movimiento de Artista Chicano" by Olga M. Martínez)
  - Ruíz, Alma, 2002 (Box 24, Folder 45)
    (note to TYF from Ruíz, 01/16/2002)
  - Ruíz-Bayon, Patricia, 1991-1993 (Box 24, Folder 46)
    (artist's statements; illustrations of installations; letter to Ruí-Bayon from TYF, 03/23/1993; letter to TYF from Ruíz-Bayon, 02/08/1993; resume; information about an exhibition in Poland; clippings)
  - Sacramento, California, 1976-1985; (clippings) (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Sala Diaz, Residence of Alejandro Diaz, Converted into Gallery, San Antonio, Texas, 2000; (clipping) (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Salazar, Daniel, circa 1995; (notecards with Salazar's art work) (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Saldaña, Martin, 1977, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
    (clippings; TYF's notes - 2 reference notes)
  - Saldívar, José David (see: Montoya, José) (Box 25)
  - Salinas, Raúl, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    (letter to TYF from Luis Mendoza, 05/17/1994, re. the "Salinas archives")
  - Salud, Dinero y Amor y Tiempo Para Gozarlos, Exhibition, Department of Health Education and Welfare, Washington, DC, undated; (exhibition booklet) (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - A Salute to Latinas in the Arts (see also: Alicia, Juana; Castillo, Ana; Hernández, Ester; Lomas Garza, Carmen; López, Yolanda; Portillo, Lourdes), 1993 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    (issue of the journal Contemporary Political Analysis & Left Dialogue)
  - Salvo, Dana, 1987-1990; (see also: Altars; Photography; Box 31) (Box 25, Folder 8)
    (clippings; resume; essays on Salvo's work; press releases; exhibition announcements; oversize exhibition poster; postcard to TYF from Pancho, 08/11/1990; letter to TYF from Salvo, 04/18/1989; letter to Salvo from Juan [illegible], Scheinbaum & Russek Dealers of Rare and Contemporary Photography, 04/06/1990; color photographs by Salvo, contact prints)
  - San Anto Cultural Arts, 2000; (clipping) (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - San Diego, California (see also: Avalos, David; Centro Cultural de La Raza), 1983-1985; (2 folders; clippings; brochures) (Box 25, Folder 10-11)
  - San Francisco Museum of Art, San Francisco, California, 1975-1976; (catlogs; exhibition announcement; clipping) (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - San Jose State University, San Jose, California, 1982; (catalog; exhibition announcement; press release) (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Sánchez, Marta, 2001-2003 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    (clipping; exhibition announcements; resume; Christmas card to TYF from Sánchez)
  - Sánchez, Robert, 1982, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    (catalog; artist's statement)
  - Sánchez-Tranquilino, Marcos, 1987-1993, undated (Box 25, Folder 16)
    (clippings; note to TYF from Sánchez-Tranquilino, 11/11/1991; outline for proposed book and photocopies of letters from Sánchez-Tranquilino to Cecelia F. Klein, Jodi Callan, Rev. William J. Donnelly; letters to TYF from Sánchez-Tranquilino, 09/23/1991, 10/07/1992, 01/24/1992; resume)
  - Sandoval, Carlos (see also: Colorado), 1980; (clippings) (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Sandoval, Ron, 1982; (clipping) (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Santa Ana College, Santa Ana, California (see also: Goldman, Shifra), 1984, undated (Box 25, Folder 19)
    (exhibition announcement; catalog essay by Shifra Goldman; exhibition poster)
  - Santeros (San Isidro Labrador), circa 2003 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    (postcard to Dudley Brooks from [illegible], undated)
  - Santistevan, Carlos Antonio, undated; (clipping) (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Santos y Santeros, 1951-1983, undated (Box 25)
    - Colorado (see also: Colorado), 1951; (clipping) (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - General, circa 1970-1993; (3 folders) (Box 25, Folder 23-25)
      (clippings; TYF's notes on saints; student essays; TYF's notes on an exhibition; catalogs; exhibition announcement; pictures of saints; TYF's notes: bibliography, and on José Rafael Aragón)
    - New Mexico (see also: Galeráa de la Raza/Studio 24), 1977-1993; (catalog; exhibition announcements; clippings; press release) (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - Santos, Margaret (see also: Posters), undated; (list of posters) (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - Santoyo, Luis, 1980; (exhibition booklet; National Hispanic Heritage Week programs) (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - Saucedo, José (see also: Theater), 1995; (fundraising event announcement) (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - "Secular Santos", 2003 (Box 25, Folder 30)
    (essay by Monica Garza)
  - Self-Help Graphics, Organization, Los Angeles, California, 1980-2004, undated; (4 folders; see also: Carrasco, Barbara; Delgado, Roberto; Galería Otra Vez; Gamboa, Diane; García, Margaret; Goldman, Shifra; Gronk; Healy, Wayne; Hernandez, Ester; Luján, Magu; Valadez, John; Valdez, Patssi) (Box 25, Folder 31-34)
    (exhibition announcements; catalogs; program brochures; clippings; event announcements; workshop schedule; organization history; bound volume, Self-Help Graphics & Art Celebrating 30 Years "In the Heart of East LA"; press release; invitations; catalog, Across the Street: Self-Help Graphics and Chicano Art in los Angeles, Laguna Art Museum, Laguna Beach, California, 1995; newsletter, Winter 2002; generic letter to TYF from Tomas Benitez, Director Self-Help Graphics, 06/06/2003; 2 numbered prints by [Wayne] Healy, 2002)
  - Seminario Permanente de Estudios Chicano y de Fronteras, Seminar, El Museo de El Carmen, Mexico, 1989; (booklet; schedule) (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - Sepúlveda, Artemio (see also: Goldman, Shifra), 1982, undated (Box 25, Folder 36)
    (clippings, one by Shifra Goldman)
  - 17 Artists: Hispano/Mexican-American/Chicano, Exhibition, Witte Memorial Museum, San Antonio, Texas, and Elsewhere (see also: The Mexican Museum; Quirarte, Jacinto), 1976-1977 (Box 25, Folder 37)
    (2 catalogs, from Witte Memorial Museum, and The Mexican Museum, introduction by Jacinto Quirarte)
  - Los Siete de la Raza, circa 1969 (Box 25, Folder 38)
    (booklet, Basta Ya! The Story of Los Siete de la Raza)
  - Sifuentes, Roberto (see also: Rasquachismo), undated (Box 25, Folder 39)
    (Spanish translation of TYF's essay, Rasquachismo: A Chicano Sensibility and receipt)
  - Sigüenza, Herbert (see also: Carrillo, Graciela; Fusco, Coco; Mission Cultural Center), 1980 (Box 25, Folder 40)
    (catalog with note to TYF from PR; exhibition announcements)
  - Silva, Ernest, 1981; (clipping) (Box 25, Folder 41)
  - Sin Nombre: Hispana and Hispano Artists of the New Deal Era, Exhibition, Museum of New Mexcio Museum of International Folk Art, Santa Fe, New Mexico (see also: Flore y Canto: Reflections From Nuevo Mexico), 1999, 2001 (Box 25, Folder 42)
    (clippings; exhibition announcement; catalog; self-guided tour booklet; artist list; report - fax; Christmas card to TYF from Tey Marianna Nunn and Jim Ross, 2001)
  - Siqueiros, David Alfaro, Painter (1896-1974; see also: Goldman, Shifra; Treviño, Jesús), 1977-1978 (Box 25, Folder 43)
    (clippings of essays by Shifra Goldman and Jesús Treviño; catalog)
  - Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C., 1994-1997 (Box 25)
    - Asian American A***, 1997, circa 1997; (clipping; fellowship announcement) (Box 25, Folder 44)
    - Hamlet Paoletti, 1996 (Box 25, Folder 45)
      (memo to TYF Chair, Latino Oversight Committee, from Miguel Bretos, Counselor to the Secretary, re. memo to TYF from Hamlet Paoletti, Chair Latino Working Committee, 11/25/1996)
    - Hispanic Heritage Month Schedule of Events, 1997; (calendar of events) (Box 25, Folder 46)
    - Hispanic Initiative Meeting, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 47)
      (memo summarizing May 3, 1994 meeting; photocopies of pages from calendar; National Museum of American History Organization Chart)
    - Institute of the Americas Draft, 1997 (Box 25, Folder 48)
      (draft of proposal for an organization to be formed within the Smithsonian)
    - "Latino Cultural Organizations and the Smithsonian: A Conversation,", 1997 (Box 25, Folder 49)
      (meeting of Latino Cultural Organizations, 05/09/1997, The Smithsonian Institution, 1100 Jefferson Drive, S.W., Washington D.C.; summary written by TYF; typed transcript of the meeting)
    - Latino Graduate Training Seminar, 1996; (seminar announcement; seminar packet) (Box 25, Folder 50)
    - Latino Graduate Training Seminar, 1997 (Box 25, Folder 51)
      (letter to TYF from Magdalena Mieri, 05/12/1997, re. TYF's participation; agenda; information on the participants; brochure)
    - Latino Museums: A National Conversation, Symposium (October 24 1996), 1996-1997 (Box 25, Folder 52)
      (TYF's notes from the symposium; memo with attached information planned events planned for 1998 sesquisentennial of Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo, centennial Spanish-American War, etc., 10/18/1996; invitation; memo with attached agenda, biographies of participants and museum mission statements; typescript of address given by Luis R. Cancel; fax to Smithsonian Friends from Edmundo DeLeon, The White House Initiative on Educational Excellence for Hispanic Americans, 01/10/1997, with attachments providing "information on the commission, initiative and the report"; Latino Studies Center Proposed Budget - fax)
    - "Latino Museums and the Smithsonian,", 1996, circa 1998, undated (Box 25, Folder 53)
      (clipping of essay, "A Place at the Table: Latino Museums and the Smithsonian Institution" by Jonathan Yorba; 1 page of TYF's notes from a Latino Oversight Committee meeting; application statements for the 1996 Latino Graduate Training Seminar)
  - Smithsonian Institution continued (Box 26)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 03/09/1995), 1994-1996 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      (meeting agenda; photocopy of letter to TYF from I. Michael Heyman, Secretary, Smithsonian Institution, 02/27/1995 re. formation of the Latino Oversight Committee with enclosures; letter to I. Michael Heyman from TYF, 03/06/1995; letter to I. Michael Heyman from John E. Huerta, 03/21/1995, cc: TYF; typescript of I. Michael Heyman's installation address; Smithsonian Institution fact sheets; letter to Contance Berry Newman, Under Secretary Smithsonian Institution, from TYF, 01/31/1996, photocopy; letter to Miguel Bretos from Gilberto Cardenas, 02/26/1995, cc: TYF; faxes to and from members of the committee)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 08/09/1995; see also: Smithsonian - Willful Neglect), 1994-1995 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      (memo to Members, Oversight Committee from Miguel Bretos, 08/09/1995; other memos not directed to TYF but regarding the LOC and the Report of the Latino Task Force; Smithsonian Institution Marketing Study Final Report; LOC meeting minutes, 05/12/1995 and 07/24/1995)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 09/19/1995) (Box 26, Folder 3)
      (photocopy of letter to Eric Reuther from TYF, 09/08/1995; photocopy of letter to I. Michael Heyman from TYF, 09/08/1995; minutes of conference call, 08/14/1995; clippings; meeting minutes, 09/19/1995; memo to LOC from Miguel Bretos, 11/06/1995; letter to TYF from I. Michael Heyman, 06/03/1996)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 01/12/1996), (draft agenda) (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 03/06/1996) (Box 26, Folder 5)
      (fax to TYF from Neil G. Kotler, 03/05/1996, with clipping; photocopy of memo to Miguel Bretos from Gilbert Cardenas, 02/08/1996, re. Latino Pool Funds/Feasibility Study-Revisions; draft agenda; press release; meeting miutes; proposal for the creation of a: Center for Latin American Research in Anthropology - CLARA, draft)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 03/18/1996) (Box 26, Folder 6)
      (packet with agenda, minutes, letter to the Under Secretary from the Chair, Latino Pool Awards, Feasibility Study letter, IUP Latino Gradfuate Semiar announcement; FY '95 Latino Pool Project Accomplishment Summary and Reports, Latino Newsletter, 150th Birthday Celebration Press Materials, schedule and list of Smithsonian Los Angeles Exhibition objects; fax to TYF from Miguel Bretos, 03/15/1996, with clipping)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 05/04/1996) (Box 26, Folder 7)
      (typescript of address given by I. Michael Heyman to the American Association of Museums, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 05/04/1996; clipping)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 05/15/1996) (Box 26, Folder 8)
      (memo to members - LOC, from Miguel Bretos, 05/15/1996, and enclosures: agenda, meeting minutes, responses to Latino Task Force Recommendation, 1995 Latino Pool Accomplishments; essay by Sulé Greg C. Wilson; "Recommendations made by members of the LOC, 05/20/1996; responses to Latino Task Force Recommendations with notes made by TYF; letters to TYF from Council on Foundations, 04/29/1996 fax, 05/10/1996 fax, and travel itinerary, all re. Philanthropy on the Mexico/United States Border: A Conference on Binational Collaboration and social Investment; meeting minutes)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 06/24/1996) (Box 26, Folder 9)
      (Smithsonian Total Labor Force, 1990-1995)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 08/5-6/1996) (Box 26, Folder 10)
      (letter to TYF from Magdalena Mieri, Center for Museum Studies, Smithsonian Institution, 07/16/1996; memo to LOC from Katherine Kirlin, LOC Liaison, 07/22/1996 fax; memo to LOC from Miguel Bretos, 07/29/1996; meeting agenda; meeting packet: agenda, mintues, letter from Rex Ellis, "Latinos in the Smithsonian Revisited: An Interim Report")
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 08/14/1996) (Box 26, Folder 11)
      (fax to TYF from Emily Gantz KcKay, Mosaica, 08/14/1996 with attached letter signed by TYF)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 09/19/1996) (Box 26, Folder 12)
      (agendas; clipping; meeting minutes; meeting packet: agendas, meeting minutes, calendar of dates; memo to TYF from Miguel Bretos, 09/17/1996; letter to TYF from Sarita Rodriguez, 08/20/1996; "Teodoro Vidal Collection Categories" list; E Pluribus Unum: This Divine Paradox: Report of the Commission on the Future of the Smithsonian Institution)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 10/02/1996) (Box 26, Folder 13)
      (memo to LOC from Miguel Bretos and Katharine Kirlin, 10/02/1996 fax; clipping)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 10/24-25/1996) (Box 26, Folder 14)
      (fax to TYF from Katherine Kirlin, 09/27/1996, with memos to LOC from Miguel Bretos and draft agenda; Latino Museum Directors' Meeting minutes)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 11/13/1996) (Box 26, Folder 15)
      (memo to LOC from Miguel Bretos, 11/13/1996 fax; letter to José Aguayo from Miguel Bretos, 11/06/1996 cc: TYF; letter to Miguel Bretos from José Aguayo, 11/05/1996 cc: TYF; fax to Neil Kotler from TYF, 11/22/1996, with attached letter signed by TYF)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 11/19/1996) (Box 26, Folder 16)
      (memo to LOC from Miguel Bretos, 11/19/1996; memos to Miguel Bretos re. comments on the LOC Mid-term Report; Latino Museums: A National Conversation)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 01/13/1997), 1996-1997 (Box 26, Folder 17)
      (menu; memo to LOC from Migeul Bretos, 12/30/1996 with agenda; meeting packet with agenda, meeting minutes, "resonses to LOC's mid-term Report", Elena Mayberry memo, Latino Musuem Directors Meeting--Roster of Attendees and Letters from Museums after the symposium, LOC address list; meeting minutes; Latino Program Committee Report; Smithsonian Institution Latino Employment Plan; TYF's notes on the report; report, Latinos in the Smithsonian Revisited; memo to LOC from Miguel Bretos, 02/24/1997 with fax attachment; agenda; meeting minutes; letters to Miguel Bretos, re. the Latino Museums symposium)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 01/30/1997) (Box 26, Folder 18)
      (memo to LOC from Miguel Bretos, 01/30/1997 fax with attachement)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 03/9-10/1997) (Box 26, Folder 19)
      (agenda; letter to Hamlet Paoletti from David F. Morrell, 01/23/1997 cc: TYF; memo to TYF et al. from Anna Cohn and Anne Gossett, 02/25/1997)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 05/8-9/1997) (Box 26, Folder 20)
      (outlines of LOC Final Report; faxes to LOC members re. May 8-9 meeting, including agenda; letter to TYF from Miguel Bretos, 04/06/1997 fax; meeting minutes; "Humanities Fellowships on Latino Cultural Research in a National Museum Context: Issues of Representation and Interpretation - Implementation Process"; "Rockefeller Humanities Fellowships Smithsonian Institution Inter University Program for Latino Research - Invited Museums list; "Latino Studies Center Notes, Concept, Components & Floor Plan, Budget"; clippings)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 06/25-26/1997) (Box 26, Folder 21)
      (agenda; meeting minutes; "Latino Cultural Organizations and the Smithsonian: A Conversation - Quotes and Concepts"; "Latino Museum Directors' Recommendations to the Smithsonain Institution"; clippings; memo to TYF from Katherine Kirlin, 05/12/1997 fax)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 07/31-08/31/1997) (Box 26, Folder 22)
      (agenda; letter to TYF from Jonathan Yorba, 07/29/1997; TYF's notes; "prospectus for the establishment of a Center for Latino Studies and Culture at the Smithsonian Institution"; exhibit proposal)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC 08/27/1997) (Box 26, Folder 23)
      (draft of final report)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC) Consulation Meeting with Congressional Hispanic Committee, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 24)
      (MS PowerPoint slides; clipping; letter to I. Michael Heyman from TYF, 06/26/1997; printed e-mail re. "Smithsonian Adds Latino Center")
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC) Mid-term Report, 1995-1996 (Box 26, Folder 25)
      (bound copy of the report; draft of report; memo to TYF from Eric Reuther, Office of Rep. Esteban E. Torres, 09/20/1996; letters to Eric Reuther and to I. Michael Heyman, from TYF, both 09/08/1995; letter to TYF from I. Michael Heyman, 09/10/1996)
    - Latino Affairs Oversight Committee (LOC) Press Conference, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 26)
      (agenda; typescripts of TYF's and others' remarks)
    - Latino Programs at the National Museum of American History, 1995-1996 (Box 26, Folder 27)
      (brochures; booklets; final and interim reports, 1996 Senior-junior Program for Latina/o Research; funding proposal for Latino Culture in the Unitedc States; event schedule; letter to TYF from Kristin C. Felch, Latino Initiative Project Manager, National Museum of American History, 11/25/1996; meeting minutes)
    - Latino Working Committee, 1994, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 28)
      (summary of Latino Working Committee 12/7/1994 meeting; meeting agenda; typescript of opening comments by Manuel J. Melendez; committee mission and goals; note to TYF from Manuel [Melendez], undated prior to 06/28/1995 with enclosure; event announcements)
    - Museum of the American Indian, 1994-1995 (Box 26, Folder 29)
      (meeting notes; press release with TYF's notes on the back; memo to TYF from Neil Kotler, 08/16/1995)
    - Museum of the Americas, 1996-1997 (Box 26, Folder 30)
      (viewer comments on America's Smithsonian exhibition; case statement for proposed Museum of the Americas)
    - National Museum of American Art - "Hispanic American Art,", undated; (see also: Quirarte, Jacinto) (Box 26, Folder 31)
      (collection guide, with introduction by Jacinto Quirarte, undated [post-1970])
    - Nuestros Caminos/Nuestros Historias, Exhibition, Smithsonian Institution Traveling Exhibition Service (SITES; see also: Photography), 2004 (Box 26, Folder 32)
      (exhibition booklet; exhibition announcement; invitation)
    - Regent Ibáñez Letter, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 33)
      (letter to Michael Heyman from Manuel Ibáñez, President Texas A & M University, 12/07/1995)
    - La Smithsonian, Smithsonian Institution Latino Affairs Newsletter, Vol. 1, nos. 1-2, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - Smithsonian Boards, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 35)